Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is add some controls to our game, for example.
We'll make it so that when the player presses spacebar, they'll jump inside of our game in order to
add controls to our game.
If you go over to the content folder and just right click, then go create a new folder and call this
input.
Then if you head inside here, just right click again and go input and select input mapping context
and just call this IMC underscore default.
Now, inside of this input mapping context, we're going to store and have all the controls for our
game.
If we just double click and open this up.
In order to add a new control, we need to add a new action mapping.
Although currently we don't have any action mappings, an action mapping is something that we're going
to use to have a specific control for a button.
For example, we could have an action mapping to that.
The player can jump, an action, mapping to the player could move.
So in order to create a new action mapping, if you just right click, create a new folder and just
call this actions, then if you double click and head inside here, right click and go input and select
input action.
Just cool this first 1ia underscore jump because we want to have a control for whenever the player is
jumping.
Then if you just right click and go input select input action and call this I a underscore move as we
want to have a control for whenever the player character is moving for this, I underscore move if you
open it up and here under value type change this to be access one D float.
You'll see why we do this a bit later.
But now we can just save and close this and go back to the input folder and open up the emcee default.
And here under mappings, if you select here, you should see the I.R. jump and the IMU that we just
made for now, just let the air jump and we basically created an action mapping for whenever we want
the player character to jump In order to actually trigger this and make the player jump, we need to
assign a specific key which will cause this action to occur.
I want to make it so that whenever the player presses the spacebar button, they'll trigger the jumping
inside of the player character.
So here next to this little keyboard icon, if you search and look for spacebar.
And just select it.
We'll make it so that whenever the player presses the spacebar, it calls the jumping action.
Let's create a new action, I think, for whenever the player is moving.
So I'll select this as that I move.
And in our game, our player character is going to move with two keys the A and D key.
So for this first keyboard, if you just select it and look for a scroll down and just like a and we
can make it so that there can be multiple buttons to trigger a specific action mapping.
So if you just click this, create new control binding.
And for the second key, if you look for the D button, will make it so that whenever the player presses
the A or D barn, it will trigger the move Action mapping.
There's one more thing we need to do, and that is for the A button.
If you just select here and go over to modifiers and go create new modifier.
And here if you just look for the negate modifier, just select it.
And what this basically will do is just make the value of this negative.
You'll see why we do that later.
We can now close this.
Now that we set up the controls for our game, the next thing we're going to do is set up a2d character
that we can play our game as inside of our content folder.
Let's create a new folder If we right click and go new folder and just call this player character.
Head inside this photo and just right click again and go to Blueprint class and go to all classes and
under search.
Look for paper CD.
I'm going to select this one paper Z character.
I just call this player underscore BP.
So inside of here, we're going to write all the information about how our player should behave and
act inside of our game.
So we just double click and hence out here.
The first thing we want to do is go to our components tab and go to our Sprite here.
Under our Sprite, basically, let us know how our player is going to look inside of our game.
We're going to go to our details and then go to the Sprite panel.
And remember earlier, made a bunch of little books at the start.
I want us to look for the idle flipbook and just select it.
So we can currently see this looks quite small.
So we need to make it a bit bigger so it fits inside of this capsule.
So in order to do that, just select it.
And then under here, under scale, just make sure this little anchor is checked.
And if I just increase the size of one of the values here to something like three.
Because that ankle is checked, it will scale everything uniformly.
If I just left this unchecked, I can scale this, but everything's not going to scale uniformly.
So that's why I just leave it checked when I'm scaling things.
You can also scale things by just going here to the Select and scale object tool.
This will change the three D gizmo.
And if I just let the middle one, I make sure all the three ones are highlighted.
And just like with my mouse, it'll become a bit bigger.
So I'm just going to move my sprite so it fits inside my character's capsule.
If you're not happy with the capsule collision, you can just select it and we can adjust the values
of them by changing the capsule half height and the capsule radius.
For now, I'm just going to leave it as I think it looks kind of fun.
So this is our player character right now.
If I just imported them inside of our game, they wouldn't work.
And that's because we need to make sure that our player character has a camera.
So we just select our capsule component and go ad and look for spring on.
This is what our camera is going to be attached to.
We just want to let the spring go on and rotate it so it's facing our player character.
Put the spring on selected.
Just go ahead and look for camera.
And just rotate this camera so it's facing a character.
And what, just like the spring gone.
We can adjust the target only to make it closer or further away from our player character.
Next.
Before we add the controls to our player character, I just want them working inside of our level so
we just close this and head over to window.
And go to world settings.
This will add this little tab here and here.
It's going to ask us for our game mode.
So our game mode basically tells the game what player character we should start our game as.
So we're going to create a new game mode.
So in order to do that, just right click Go Blueprint class and go game mode based and just pull this
R to the game mode.
Head inside here.
And go to default point class.
So our player, BP, is a -- blueprint.
A -- blueprint is any blueprint that can be possessed by our player character.
We just want to go to our default point class and select the player BP.
And just go compile and save.
And now here under wild settings, if I just drag in my two D game mode here.
When I start my game, I'm going to start at this play at BP in order to determine where in our world
our players are.
We can just go here to add quickly things to the product and select basic and select player START.
So our character is going to start here inside of our game.
And now if I just go play.
My game will load and this will be where my character starts.
So nice.
Everything is working.
The next thing I do is add the controls that we set up earlier, so they work with our player character.